somebody were like taking Journey down
memory lane remembering like old stuff
like macr median hypercard um metadata
what is it what is metadata and why do
you care um I don't know let's ask chat
GPT chat GPT knows all uh what is
metadata it's data about the data That's
So Meta metadata is data that provides
information about other data wow my mind
was blown in other words this data about
data it used to provide documentation
for data products and basic form
metadata answers who what when where why
and how about
everything facet of the data who made it
where it come from for example in a
photo metadata is about where it was oh
no I've given up my location so that's
what metadata is but related to HTML
where does the metadata go and the
answer to that
is right here in ins side of the head
element notice it's head element not
header not heading head okay so inside
of the head element is a an element
called title um in our code that we've
been working on you'll see that right
away uh there's a title down there so
I'm going change that to Hello World um
and autosave then you'll see that pop up
on our website here there's videos about
how to set all this up in other places
um see here it says hell world as as the
title of the page uh apparently uh
metadata is considered um I the title is
considered metadata uh even though it's
very common um to have uh a heading
match the title not always right uh we
don't have this yet we don't know about
how to do this but this would you know
this would be common uh so I just want
to throw one of these out there at you
um uh if I can do it right um
just to give you a sense of it so
they're hello world and hello world met
title but those are two different things
um so the
metadata uh for the title which is
enclosed in in the beginning and ending
title tags uh or the starting and ending
um is is in there now we have we have
other metadata in here too and this
actually has the meta keyword um and I
want to spend a little bit of time
talking about this
so
um actually I'm just going to tell you
that this metadata should be the kind of
metadata you should just add standard uh
again the way we got this is we started
HTML 5 and we picked the the template
that that was provided for us but but it
is pretty safe to say that having these
two things is very important if you want
it to be consistent um the extent of
this video is to cover the things that
are necessary to make a web page
document not an app um there's
considerably more metadata that needs to
be added if you're making an app of any
kind anything that uses JavaScript um
when you're just creating something
that's going to be a document then you
just need to tell the document what kind
of characters are being used that's what
this is and you know how the viewport
should be viewed on a phone or elsewhere
and you can look up what those
individual metadata types are about um
there's another metadata tag to
automatically redirect uh the page to
another page and again you can read
about all the metadata tags in the
standard uh and I mean I would start
with the standard if you want further
you know uh elucidation about what is in
the standard you feel free to go to
wherever you want the Milla developer
Network to html3 schools or whatever
recode camp but but start with the
standard and then if you need more more
uh explanation come come look at that so
here we go here's the title element you
can read about it here the head as no
other title element text is it gives you
the very very you know down and dirty
details about it um we are not going to
talk about the base element or the link
element for now um these are things that
are related to uh other stuff we will
talk about base when we talk about
linking later um the Bas I guess we can
talk about it the bass just tells uh the
web browser where this should be
considered um in terms for referencing
like when we're trying to to link to
some other thing so for example uh bass
this is the URL where this thing lives
and that tells the browser what it
should already kind of know based on
where it's at um and it's using a syntax
from URL links which we have not yet
talked about we'll talk about it when we
talk about links using an hre which is a
very specific attribute um used in
hyperlinks and that's what this anchor
tag is right here so those are the base
metadatas that you need um the other
ones will be talked about in other
videos particularly the style we are not
going to talk about the style element
until we talk about CSS which changes
the look and feel of a page and that
we're going to skip that for now so so
that is it that is it for metadata
there's not much to know uh there's meta
and and if you want to understand utf8
there's another video on Unicode we'll
do that um but you know that's that's it
that's it Mo the main thing is title
right you got to change the title and
that's how you do it uh and by the way
if you dynamically change that title
with the script it'll change the title
live too right where it right where it's
at there and you can do some fun things
with that so have a look at that that